Today in this video we will talk, know and
understand about the
best money bike term insurance policy
plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life. If you are looking for
such a term insurance
policy plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life in which
if nothing happens to you till the entire policy term
and you remain safe till the end of the policy, then
you get your entire
premium back at that time, then you can take
this term insurance policy plan of Adi Birla Sun Life,
which I am going to
tell you about in this video,
because here you actually get your
total premium back
at the end of the policy and along with this, you
get many other good benefits here.
Like in this you get total six types of
plan options.  From which you
can choose any one.  Here
both the options of Premium of Return and Early Premium of Return are available,
about which we will see in details later.
In this, premium is waived in case of critical illness and total
permanent disability.  The
best part is that it
offers a one-time exit value in
which you get your premium back.   In case of
any emergency, this policy
also offers inbuilt terminal exemption benefit.
Here, if you
choose the critical illness benefit by paying an additional premium,
you get coverage for 42 types of critical illnesses.
So,
without wasting much time, let us directly know about this money back
term insurance policy plan.
So its name is Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Complete Security Shield.  This is a non-
linked non-participating individual
pure risk premium life term
insurance plan.  As I
told you in the beginning, there are a total of
six types of plan options available on this policy, which are as follows.
If you want, you can choose any of these
options.  But there are
only two such plan options available
where your entire premium is
returned at the end of the policy.  The first of which is the
plan option to return of premium
option.  Here, on completion of the policy term, the
total premium is returned in the form of maturity benefit.
If the policy
holder survives and if the policy holder
dies during the policy term,
then in this condition his family gets the
lump sum amount of the problem as death benefit.
Now the next second plan
option is Early Return of Premium Option.   In
this option also the policy holder
gets his total premium back.  When the
policy anniversary is completed, that is,
here you have to choose the retirement age.
Like 60 years, 65 years, 70 years or
75 years.  And if you
survive till retirement age, you get your total
premium back.  But if the
policy holder dies before reaching the retirement age, then
in this condition his family gets the
lump sum amount of the sum assured as death benefit.
Let us understand this with an example.
Suppose there is a 35 year old Mr.
Gupta who chooses the return of
premium option of this policy in which
he takes a sum assured of ₹1 crore, policy term of 50 years
and premium payment term of 10 years.
After that, if he dies after paying the premium for 25 years, then
his
nominee i.e. the family gets a lump sum amount of ₹1 crore
as death benefit
and the policy gets terminated.  But
if Mr. Gupta survives for the full 50 years,
he gets back
his total premium of
₹847,000 as maturity benefit.  So, in the same way, the
option with early return and premium
also works.  And the main big thing is that
on this policy you also get a total of six types of riders
options which are these.
You can choose from these as per your need by
paying additional premium.  So this
is the best money back term insurance policy plan of Aitya Birla Sun Life,
which you
can take without any hesitation if you want.  But
before choosing any policy,
understand all its terms and conditions thoroughly.  So if
you found this video helpful then like it and
if you are new then subscribe to the channel and
follow the page.  So see you
in the next video.  Till then Jai Jai.  Bye-B
Thank you.